A Finding Aid to the Architectural League of New York Records, 1880s-1974, bulk 1927-1968, in the Archives of American Art AAA.archleag
Archives of American Art
- Committee Records, 1887-1974; Series 2; 44.7 Linear feet Boxes 10-54, 110, 114, OV 116
  - Membership Committee, 1897-1972; 2.5
    - Membership Census (as of Mar. 30, 1953), (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
    - Membership Directories, 1956-1970; (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 3-4)
    - Membership Drive, 1938-1940, 1950; (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 5-6)
    - Membership Drive, Associates, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Membership Drive, Non-Resident, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Membership General Information, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Membership Incentives, League and Other Organizations, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Membership Lists, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Membership Lists and Miscellaneous, 1950, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Membership Lists by Category and Profession (Mar. 1972) (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Membership Reports, 1936-1940; (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 14-15)
    - Membership Roster, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Membership Roster Corrections, 1954-1955 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Membership Schedules, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Membership Status, 1956-1960 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Membership Summary, 1953-1957; (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 20-21)
    - Membership Unfinished, 1953-1955 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Memorial Resolutions, 1951-1958 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Memorial Resolutions, Carl Milles, 1955-1957 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Minutes of Membership Committee Meetings, 1938, 1950-1960s; (7 folders) (Box 45, Folder 25-31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1912-1969; (8 folders) (Box 45, Folder 32-39)
    - Notices, 1937-1938 (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Notices to Members, $100 Charge Account, circa 1956-1957 (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Notices to Members, Advancement Notice, 1950 (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Notices to Members Regarding Dues, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - Panels, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Patrons, 1969-1970 (Box 45, Folder 45)
    - Patrons and Sustaining Members, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 46)
    - Pedrick, Lucile A. [Executive Secretary], 1940-1941, 1946-1947; (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 47-48)
    - Pedrick, Lucile A. [Executive Secretary], 1940-1941, 1946-1947 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Phone Directory, 1950-1962 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Posting List [of Members Owing Dues], 1940-1941, 1949-1950; (3 folders) (Box 46, Folder 3-5)
    - Posting List Nos. 1-5, 7 [of Members Owing Dues], 1940-1946; (6 folders) (Box 46, Folder 6-11)
    - Postponement of Dues, 1950 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Professional Designation of Members, 1954, 1956 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Proposed Member Correspondence, 1945-1960; (8 folders) (Box 46, Folder 14-21)
    - Prospects, 1937-1940, 1947-1949; (3 folders) (Box 46, Folder 22-24)
    - References on Members, 1950-1951 (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - Rejected Applications for Membership, 1950-1955 (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - Report of Membership Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - Requests for Membership Applications, 1949-1966; (5 folders) (Box 46, Folder 28-32)
    - Requests for Membership Information, 1950, 1971; (2 folders) (Box 46, Folder 33-34)
    - Requirements for Membership, Patronage, Etc. (Constitution), circa 1969 (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - Resignations, 1939-1972; (13 folders) (Box 46, Folder 36-48)
    - Resignations (Box 47)
      - Active, 1953, 1960-1964; (4 folders) (Box 47, Folder 1-4)
      - Blank Forms, 1952 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Junior, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Non-Resident, 1953-1960; (2 folders) (Box 47, Folder 7-8)
    - Resignations Accepted, 1935-1947, 1967; (4 folders) (Box 47, Folder 9-12)
    - Resignations Accepted Subject to Payment of Dues, 1943-1949; (2 folders) (Box 47, Folder 13-14)
    - Resignations Reconsidered, 1935-1946; (3 folders) (Box 47, Folder 15-17)
    - Revenue From Dues Written Off, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Roster [of Members Owing Dues], 1940 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Roster of the League, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Sample Letters to Members, 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Secretary 1933-1934 (Box 47)
      - Applications and Proposals for Membership, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - Members - Deceased, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - Members - Dropped, 1932-1934 (Box 47, Folder 24)
      - Members - Emeritus and Honorary and Inquiries re: This Class, 1933- 1934 (Box 47, Folder 25)
      - Members - Life, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - Members - Reinstated, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 27)
      - Members - Transferred, Inquiries re: Transfers, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 28)
      - Members - Transfers Pending re: Class Membership, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 29)
      - Resignations, 1932-1934 (Box 47, Folder 30)
      - Resignations Withdrawn or Reconsidered, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Secretary 1934-1935 (Box 47)
      - Alice M. Simpson Medal - Speech and Notice to Press (Dec. 14, 1934), 1934-1935 (Box 47, Folder 32)
      - Applications and Proposals for Membership, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 33)
      - Members, Emeritus and Honorary, 1933-1935 (Box 47, Folder 34)
      - Members, Women, 1934-1936 (Box 47, Folder 35)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 36)
      - Resignations, 1925, 1933-1935 (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - Secretary 1938-1939 (Box 47)
      - Address Changes, 1938-1940 (Box 47, Folder 38)
      - Applications for Membership (Approved), circa 1938-1939 (Box 47, Folder 39)
      - Chairman, Frederick J. Woodbridge, 1938-1939 (Box 47, Folder 40)
      - Collection Agencies - Dues, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 41)
      - Committee on Membership, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 43)
      - Information and Inquiries re: Memberships, 1938-1939 (Box 47, Folder 44)
      - Invitation to Join League, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 45)
      - January Panel for Recruiting New Members, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 46)
      - Lists of Members, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 47)
      - Members, Deceased, 1938-1939 (Box 47, Folder 48)
      - Members, Elected, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 49)
      - Requests for Membership List, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 50)
    - Secretary 1939-1940 (Box 47)
      - Address Changes, 1939-1940 (Box 47, Folder 51)
      - Dues Collection, 1940 (Box 47, Folder 52)
      - Members, Deceased, 1938-1940 (Box 47, Folder 53)
      - Members, Women, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 54)
      - Requests for Membership List, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    - Secretary 1941-1942 (Box 48)
      - Circulars (Notices to Members), 1940-1943 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - List of New Members Since Year Book Was Printed 1940, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Resolutions, Deceased, 1941-1943 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Secretary [1942-1943], References re: Members (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Secretary 1944-1945, Members, Deceased, 1944-1947 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Sharp, J. Stanley (Special Committee to Secure New Members), 1949 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Special Membership Meeting, Annual Meeting (Mar. 16, 1966) (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Statement of Who We Are, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Stimulating Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Student Memberships, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Summary of Members Dues, 1958-1965 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Transfer Status, 1945-1968 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Transfers, 1945-1952; (2 folders) (Box 48, Folder 13-14)
    - Transfers (Box 48)
      - Active, 1956-1958 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Active to Non-Resident, 1948-1965; (2 folders) (Box 48, Folder 16-17)
      - Active to Non-Resident, Andrew Reinhard, 1957 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - Associate to Active, 1942-1953; (5 folders) (Box 48, Folder 19-23)
      - Associate to Non-Resident, 1949-1953 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - Pending Requests to Change Status to Non-Resident (and Received Non-Resident), 1935-1938 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Transfers to Active, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Transfers to Emeritus, 1953-1959; (2 folders) (Box 48, Folder 27-28)
    - Transfers to Non-Resident, 1948-1949; (3 folders) (Box 48, Folder 29-31)
    - Travel Benefit Information, circa 1970 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Treasurer, Albert W. Butt, re: Data on Former Members "Dropped,", 1947-1949 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Treasurer, John W. Pickworth, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Treasury Department re: Kamal Yakoup, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - Member Cards, Diagrams Submitted by Gustave Jensen, circa 1950; (Oversized materials from Box 39, Folder 52) (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Scholarships and Special Awards Committee, 1927-1973; 2.6
    The Scholarships and Special Awards Committee's activities managing and awarding scholarships are documented through correspondence, meeting minutes, receipts, citations, and scholarship applications. Scholarships and awards found here include Henry O. Avery Award, Arthur W. Brunner Award, Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize, Michael Friedsam Medal, Howard Myers Award, and J. Clawson Mills Fellowship. National Gold Medal records are found in the Exhibitions series.
    - 1964 Resolution re: Administration Fee for Funds (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Accounting of Scholarship Funds, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Announcements [From Scrapbook?], 1972 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (Box 48)
      - Correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 48, Folder 39)
      - List of Recipients, 1960-1964 (Box 48, Folder 40)
      - "Power in Buildings," Hugh Ferriss Book, circa 1949-1953 (Box 48, Folder 41)
      - Recipients' Accounts, circa 1965 (Box 48, Folder 42)
      - Recipients' Agreements, 1950s-1960s (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1953), Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, "Anonymous Architecture of the Western Hemisphere,", 1953-1957 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1955), Harold V. Walsh, "Development in Building Techniques,", 1954-1959 (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award [1955], Harold V. Walsh, "Revolution in American Construction" Typescript, (3 folders) (Box 48, Folder 46-48)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1956), Henry Hope Reed, Jr., 1956-1959 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1958), Applications Submitted, 1958-1961; (2 folders) (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1958), Paul Damaz, 1958-1959 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1959), Pier Luigi Nervi (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1962), Final Applications, 1962-1963 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1962), Eleanor Pepper, 1962-1967 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1963) (Box 49)
      - Announcements and Applications, 1962-1963 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Applicants and Correspondence, 1963 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Kriebel $amp; Kriebel, 1968-1969 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Kriebel $amp; Kriebel, "Stairs" (1st Award), 1963-1965 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Robert L. Zion, "Trees for Architecture" (2nd Award), 1963 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1964) (Box 49)
      - Announcement and Application Forms, 1963-1964 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - David Kenneth Specter (1st Award), 1964-1966 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - John Jay Stonehill, 1963-1964 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - John Jay Stonehill (2nd Award), 1964-1965 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1965), circa 1965 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1965) (Box 49)
      - Announcements and Application Forms, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - Applicants and Correspondence, 1944, 1964-1966 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - John E. Flynn, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - John E. Flynn, "The Role of Environmental Systems in Building Design,", 1966 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1966) (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1966) (Box 49)
      - Applications, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 22)
      - Myron H. Goldfinger, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 23)
      - Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (Pre-1967), 1964, 1967 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1968) (Box 49)
      - Applications, circa 1967 (Box 49, Folder 26)
      - W. Joseph Black, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 27)
      - Press Follow-Up, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 28)
      - Press Releases, Publicity, Expenses, circa 1968 (Box 49, Folder 29)
      - Requests for Applications, circa 1968 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1969) (Box 49)
      - Applications (Completed), 1969 (Box 49, Folder 31)
      - J. Hugh Burgess, 1969-1970 (Box 49, Folder 32)
      - John Fulop, Jr., 1969 (Box 49, Folder 33)
      - Press Release, Letters, Etc., 1969 (Box 49, Folder 34)
      - Press Releases, Publicity, Expenses, 1968-1969 (Box 49, Folder 35)
      - Requests for Applications, 1968-1969 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1970) (Box 49)
      - Announcements and Press Release, 1969-1970 (Box 49, Folder 37)
      - Application and Flyer, 1969-1970 (Box 49, Folder 38)
      - John M. Bailey, Jr., 1970-1971 (Box 49, Folder 39)
      - Mailing Lists, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 40)
      - Payments Outstanding, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 41)
      - Requests for Applications, 1969-1970 (Box 49, Folder 42)
    - Arnold W. Brunner Award (1971) (Box 49)
      - Announcement, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 43)
      - Competition Results, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 44)
      - Requests for Applications, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 45)
    - Art News, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 46)
    - Avery Award (1950s), 1951-1957, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - Avery Fund and Birch Burdette Long Memorial Fund, 1944-1956; (3 folders) (Box 49, Folder 48-50)
    - Avery Fund and Birch Burdette Long Memorial Fund, Ralph Walker, 1938-1949 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - Award Citations, 1958-1963; (Oversized materials housed in Box 110, Folder 3) (Box 49, Folder 52)
    - Awards Recipients, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Battery Park Competition, circa 1948 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Fund, 1927 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Fund, 1945, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Fund Competition, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize, 1940s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (Box 50)
      - Correspondence re: Announcement, 1930s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Lists of Recipients, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Mailing Data, 1968-1970 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Origin and History by Chester B. Price, 1957-1960s (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1951), Robert Schwartz ($200) (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1953), T. Trip Russell and 2 Hon. Men., 1953, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1955) (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1956), George Cooper Rudolph and 3 Hon. Men. (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1957), Elliott Glushak and 2 Hon. Men. (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1962), Recipients, 1962-1964 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1963), Chairman, Minor L. Bishop, Renderings (Mar. 28, 1963), 1962- 1964 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1963), Winners (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1964), Architectural Renderings, 1950s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1965), Competition Forms (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1965), Ara Derderian; Hon. Men. Vincent Furno and Zvonimir Tesla (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1967), Application List, 1965-1967 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1968), 1950s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1968), Applications, circa 1966-1968 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1968), Requests, 1967-1968 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1970) (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize (1970), Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize Announcements (From 1951-1965) (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize Citations, 1953, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - Birch Burdette Long Memorial Prize Rendering Competition (Mar. 23, 1967) (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - Budgets and Balances, All Funds, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - Chairman (Box 50)
      - Richard F. Bach, 1949-1950 (Box 50, Folder 32)
      - Armand Bartos, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 33)
      - Hugh Ferriss, 1958-1959 (Box 50, Folder 34)
      - Charles H. Magruder, 1941, 1951-1956 (Box 50, Folder 35)
      - Hildreth Meiere, 1938-1964 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Committee on Scholarships and Special Awards, 1941-1955; (5 folders) (Box 50, Folder 37-41)
    - Correspondence, circa 1964-1969; (2 folders) (Box 50, Folder 42-43)
    - Correspondence and Minutes, 1942-1965; (5 folders) (Box 51, Folder 1-5)
    - Current Work 1939-1940, Smithsonian Competition Drawings (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Financial Calculations, 1950s-1960s (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Foundations, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Competition, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Governing Procedures, Administrative Fees, Legal Problems Concerning Scholarships, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Henry O. Avery Prize, 1948, 1960s (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Howard Myers Award (Box 51)
      - Correspondence, 1950s; (2 folders) (Box 51, Folder 12-13)
      - Fund Data, circa 1952-1960 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Lists of Magazines, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Procedure, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Howard Myers Award (1951), Walter Gropius (1st Award), circa 1950-1951 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Howard Myers Award (1953), Lewis Munford (2nd Award), circa 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Howard Myers Award (1956), Eero Saarinen (3rd Award), 1954-1957 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Howard Myers Award (1959), Peter Blake (4th Award), 1960 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Invoices, Clark & Way, Inc., 1960 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Invoices, Medallic Art Co., 1954-1957 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - J. Clawson Mills Fellowship, 1966-1968; (2 folders) (Box 51, Folder 23-24)
    - J. Clawson Mills Fellowship (Box 51)
      - Account of Funds, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - Robert A.M. Stern, 1965-1966 (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - Will and Legal Papers, 1943, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - J. Clawson Mills Fellowship (1966) (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - J. Clawson Mills Fellowship (1966) (Box 51)
      - Michael Baker, 1966-1969; (2 folders) (Box 51, Folder 29-30)
      - General, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - Landscape Architecture, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - Sculpture, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 33)
      - W. Todd Williams, 1966-1968 (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - J. Clawson Mills Fund Exhibition No. 4, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - Jefferson Memorial Competition, Chairman, Charles Macgruder, 1947-1948 (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - Koren-DiResta Construction Co., 1969 (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - Koren-DiResta Scholarship, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 38)
    - Lectures Committee Meeting, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 39)
    - Lists of Awards, 1950s-1960s (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - Lists of Committee Members, 1960s-1970 (Box 51, Folder 41)
    - Mastic Tile Corp. of America Annual Design Competition, 1958-1961 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Medal Awards (Citations Used for the Various Awards From 1929-1938), 1930s (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Medal of Honor, Chairman, Julian C. Levi, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Meeting Notes in Shorthand, circa 1960s (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award, 1936-1960s; (3 folders) (Box 52, Folder 5-7)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1936), Copies of Citations, 1936-1966 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1939), John Davison Rockefeller, Jr., 1953 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1940), Frederick P. Keppel (17th Award) (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1952), Arthur Amory Houghton (21st Award), circa 1952 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1953), Correspondence, 1940s-1950s (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1955), James William Fulbright (22nd Award) (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1957), Aileen Osborn Webb (23rd Award) (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1958), Otto Lucien Spaeth (24th Award), 1958, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1960), Walter Paepcke, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1963), Thomas J. Watson, Jr. (26th Award) (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1968), 1967-1969 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award (1969), Mayor John V. Lindsay (June 19, 1969) (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award Dinner, Seymour Knox (Feb. 23, 1966), 1940, 1966; (3 folders) (Box 52, Folder 20-22)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Award Dinner, Dr. Frank Stanton (Apr. 16, 1964) (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Cast, undated (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Michael Friedsam Medal Fellowship in Honor of Frederick P. Keppel (May 9, 1940) (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Minutes of Scholarships and Special Awards Committee Meetings, 1941-1973; (9 folders) (Box 52, Folder 26-34)
    - New Awards Program, Der Scutt and John Lobell, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Otto R. Eggers Award, 1969, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Otto R. Eggers Fund, 1964-1965 (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Otto R. Eggers Fund, Deposit Slips, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - President's Medal, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - President's Medal to John Davison Rockefeller, Jr., circa 1953 (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Secretary 1938-1939, Smithsonian Competition, Architectural Services, 1939, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Secretary 1942-1943, Citation Awarded to Fletcher Collins (Box 52, Folder 42)
    - Small House Competition in Connection With "Building Your Home Show" and Book "Before You Buy a House,", circa 1954 (Box 52, Folder 43)
    - Summary of Awards - List of Scholarships, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - U.S.A. Tomorrow Manhattan Redevelopment Competition (Co-Sponsored), 1956 (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Award Citations, 1958-1963; (Oversized materials from Box 49, Folder 52) (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Various Committees, 1905-1974; 2.7
    This subseries includes files of various committees not in the previous subseries. Materials found include administrative files of committees, agendas, committee lists, correspondence, election records, and Secretary's Files from 1938-1944. Additional scattered committee records are found in the Photographic Materials series.
    - Action Committee, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Advisory Committee on League Problems, 1941, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Agendas, 1936-1949, 1960-1965; (7 folders) (Box 53, Folder 3-9)
    - Agendas, Fine Arts Federation, 1948-1949 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Agendas (With Unfinished Items Carried Forward, May 1, 1939), 1936-1941 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Announcements to New Members, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Architects' Emergency Committee, 1948 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Audit Committee, 1950, 1953; (2 folders) (Box 53, Folder 14-15)
    - Building Craftsman Committee, 1917-1918 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Committee Lists, 1949-1955; (2 folders) (Box 53, Folder 17-18)
    - Committee Members Lists, 1943-1957; (3 folders) (Box 53, Folder 19-21)
    - Committee on Admissions, Meeting Minutes, 1905-1909 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Analysis (Special), Chairman, Alfred Geiffert, Jr., 1949-1950 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Committee on Government and Art, 1950-1951 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Committee on Inter-American Cooperation, Mrs. Keep, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 25)